Guide to the Robert Price Papers, 1930s-2012 (bulk 1958-1965) MS 3130
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Other political activities & material, 1930s-2012
  - Deputy Mayor. Speech: "Is City Government Obsolete?", 1966 June 4 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    Remarks before the Governor's Conference on Decisions for Progress, Olympic Hotel, Seattle, Washington.
  - Deputy Mayor. Speech: "Coming Political Struggle" (notes), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
  - Abraham Lincoln quotation & correspondence, 1968 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
    Multiple copies of an Abraham Lincoln quotation: "If I were trying to read, much less answer all the attacks made on me, this shop might well be closed for any other business. I do the best I know how, the very best I can; and I mean to keep on doing it to the end. If the end brings me out all right, what is said against me will not amount to anything. If the end brings me out all wrong, ten angels swearing I was right would make no difference." With carbon copies of letters by which Robert Price sent the quotation to various officials and businessmen throughout the United States.
  - Richard Nixon cabinet, 1968 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
    Issues of TIME (December 20, 1968) and Newsweek (December 23, 1968) profiling the incoming cabinet of President Richard Nixon.
  - Op-Eds, 1974-2012 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gerald Ford, 1975-2000 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    Material exploring Robert Price's possible involvement in the political activities of the 38th President after his term's end.
  - Jimmy Carter, 1979 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    Newspaper clippings regarding Robert Price's possible appointment to a special counsel post to supervise a federal investigation of President Carter's family peanut business. The Carter family business received loans totalling $7 million from the National Bank of Georgia authorized by former federal Budget Director Bert Lance.
  - Donald Rumsfeld [2 folders], 1980-1986 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10-11)
    Donald H. Rumsfeld, United States Secretary of Defense under Gerald Ford and George W. Bush, briefly sought the Republican nomination for president in 1988.
  - Campaign samples. New York [folder 1 of 4], 1930s-1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12)
    • Jack BALTZELL and Alice SACHS
    • Bruce BARTON
    • Lester BAUM
    • LaFollette BECKER
    • Frederic S. BERMAN
    • Matthew H. BRANDENBURG
    • Charles D. BREITEL
    • John R. BROOK
    • Frederick BRYAN
    • John J. BURNS
    • John M. BURNS
    • Samuel C. CANTOR
    • William A. CARROLL
    • Samuel C. COLEMAN
    • Robert T. CONNOR
    • Edward CORSI
    • John ELLIS
    • Burton M. FINE
  - Campaign samples. New York [folder 2 of 4], 1930s-1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 13)
    • Charles GOLD
    • Dick GREGORY
    • Jacob GRUMET
    • W. Averell HARRIMAN
    • Burton G. HECHT
    • Stanley M. ISAACS
    • Jacob "Jack" JAVITS
    • Jules J. JUSTIN
    • Ken KEATING
    • KENNEDY-JOHNSON
    • John F. KENNEDY [Ticket and program to JFK's birthday celebration at Madison Square Garden, May 19, 1962.]
    • Robert F. KENNEDY
    • Edward I. KOCH
    • Theodore KUPFERMAN
    • John LAMULA
    • Louis J. LEFKOWITZ
    • Herbert H. LEHMAN
    • Arthur LEVITT
    • Charles D. LIEBER
    • J. Edward LUMBARD
    • James A. LUNDY
  - Campaign samples. New York [folder 3 of 4], 1930s-1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 14)
    • Tom MALLEE
    • George J. MINTZER
    • Francis T. MURPHY Jr.
    • William H. McINTYRE
    • New York State Supreme Court
    • Richard M. NIXON
    • William F. PASSANNANTE
    • Samuel R. PIERCE Jr.
    • Henry V. POOR
    • Ogden REID
    • John H. RAY
    • Gilbert A. ROBINSON
    • William F. RYAN
  - Campaign samples. New York [folder 4 of 4], 1930s-1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 15)
    • Warren L. SCHNUR
    • Paul R. SCREVANE
    • Benjamin SHALLECK
    • Maxwell SHAPIRO
    • William S. SHEA
    • Daniel STEINER
    • Robert K. STRAUS
    • Gerald H. ULLMAN
    • James B. WALKER Jr.
    • Fred WARDER
    • Malcolm WILSON
  - Campaign samples. Non-New York, 1950s-1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 16)
    • William H. AYRES
    • E. Y. BERRY
    • Hamer BUDGE
    • Charles E. CHAMBERLAIN
    • Louis W. COLLIER
    • Edward J. DERWINSKI
    • Samuel L. DEVINE
    • Doug ELLIOTT
    • Samuel N. FRIEDEL
    • Cecil HARDEN
    • Joe HOLT
    • Craig HOSMER
    • Richard J. HUGHES
    • Melvin R. LAIRD
    • Glen LIPSCOMB
    • George Cabot LODGE
    • Charles McC. MATHIAS
    • James P. MITCHELL
    • F. Bradford MORSE
    • Hjalmar C. NYGAARD
    • Albert H. QUIE
    • Richard RICHARDS
    • Milnor ROBERTS [33 & 1/3-RPM floppy record]
    • William SCRANTON
    • Abner W. SIBAL
    • John K. TABOR
    • Stan TUPPER
    • George VAVOULIS
    • Wheelock WHITNEY
    • Bob WILSON
    • Wendell WYATT
    • J. Arthur YOUNGER
  - Campaign samples. Bumper stickers [8 items], 1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 17)
    • CONNOR FOR CONGRESS [2 copies]
    • GOLDWATER / MILLER
    • JOHNSON / HUMPHREY FOR THE USA
    • KENNEDY U.S. SENATOR [Robert F. Kennedy]
    • RE-ELECT VAVOULIS MAYOR [George Vavoulis] [3 copies]
  - Campaign samples. Bottle stoppers [2 items], undated (Offsite-box 8, Box 8c)
    "Colorful Plastic Bottle Caps for your opened soft drink bottles. They will keep your beverages fresh and sparkling for weeks." Apparently customizable, the two examples present are printed with "The Winchester Bank" and "SAKRETE." Perhaps Robert Price considered using bottle caps as a form of campaign advertisement.
  - Campaign samples. Buttons & lapel pins [18 items], undated (Offsite-box 8, Box 8c)
    • For Congress AKERS 17th District
    • CONNOR for Congress [3 copies]
    • GOLDWATER
    • I / HATE / BARRY [Goldwater]
    • IRM
    • Bill MILLER [with portrait]
    • Bill MILLER for Veep
    • New York State Citizens Committee
    • NIXON
    • NIXON '60 Now!
    • Relax
    • Bill SCRANTON
    • SCRANTON for President
    • Elect SCREVANE Mayor
    • STEVENSON
    • Bill VANDEN HEUVEL for Congress
  - Campaign samples. Ink stamp, undated (Offsite-box 8, Box 8c)
    PAY TO THE ORDER OF / FIRST NATIONAL CITY BANK / PARK AVENUE - 46th STREET BRANCH / Committe For New York Government Candidates.
  - Campaign samples. Nail files [4 items], undated (Offsite-box 8, Box 8c)
    • Elect / JOHN W. HAHN / Councilman
    • Re-Elect / Wm. H. HESS / to Congress
    • Re-Elect / TOM V. MOORHEAD / State Senator
    • SAY / I'M FOR NIXON / VOTE REPUBLICAN
  - Convention pins, ribbons, etc. [10 items], 1948-1964 (Offsite-box 8, Box 8c)
    • Honorary Assistant Sergeant at Arms / 1948 / Philadelphia Republican National Convention [lapel ribbon]
    • St. Olaf College Political Emphasis Week 1962
    • Delegate Republican State Convention Sept. 18-19, 1962, Buffalo, New York [lapel ribbon]
    • New York Republican State Committee Guest
    • N Y COUNTY [with Republican elephant]
    • Republican National Convention San Francisco 1964 "Bob Price" [name tag]
    • Republican National Convention San Francisco 1964 "Radio - T.V." [name tag]
    • Delegate San Francisco 1964 / Air Transport Association Flying Elephant Club [key]
    • [pink envelope printed "KEY" holding 2 small keys]
  - Publications. Campaign Technique Manual, circa 1960s-1970s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 18)
  - Publications. Democratic County Handbook, circa 1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 19)
  - Publications. Republican Party, National, circa 1950s-1960s (Offsite-box 4, Folder 20)
  - Publications. Republican Party, New York, circa 1958-1964 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 21)
  - Publications. Voter registration guides & ephemera, circa 1952-1960 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 22)
  - Shoup Voting Machine Corporation sample, undated (Offsite-box 8, Box 8d)
    A portable, mechanical sample of the type of lever voting machine common at New York polling places before the introduction of electronic scanners. The Shoup Voting Machine Corporation, founded in 1905 by Samuel R. Shoup, eventually came to be called Advanced Voting Solutions, Inc., before going out of business in 2015.
- Series IV. Price professional, 1958-1990
  Series IV contains material spanning Robert Price's evolving professional career, from his days as a law clerk serving Judge Archie Owen Dawson of United States District Court, Southern District of New York, to his law partnership with Theodore R. Kupferman, through his days with the Dreyfus Fund (investment firm) and Lazard Frères & Co. (investment bankers), and his own Price Capital Corporation and Price Communications Corporation. Coverage is spotty.
  - Robert Price, "Monetary Remedies Under the Untied States Copyright Code", 1958-1959 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 23)
    Published in Fordham Law Review, vol. 27, no. 4 (Winter 1958–59), 555–578. [Folder contains complete issue and offprint.]
  - Robert Price, "The Admissibility of Wiretap Evidence in the Federal Courts", 1959 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 24)
    Published in University of Miami Law Review, vol. 14 (1959), 57–71. [Folder contains offprint.]
  - United States District Court, Southern and Eastern Districts of New York [2 folders], 1958-1959 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 25-26)
    Robert Price served as law clerk to Judge Archie Owen Dawson, United States District Court, Southern District of New York, 1958–1959, and as Assistant United States Attorney, Southern District of New York, 1959–1960.
  - United States Court of Appeals, Second Circuit [3 folders], 1959-1960 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 27-29)
  - Kupferman & Price, 1960-1965 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
    Law partnership of Robert Price and Theodore R. Kupferman; dissolved in 1965 when Price was appointed Deputy Mayor of New York City. [Attorney and New York City council member Theodore Kupferman (1920-2003) would succeed to John Lindsay's vacated seat in the U.S. House of Representatives from New York's 17th district, serving February 8, 1966 – January 3, 1969.]
  - Columbia Broadcasting System [CBS] annual report, 1960 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic States Industries, 1964 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
  - United States Jaycees [Junior Chamber of Commerce] award [2 folders], 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4-5)
    Robert Price was named one of the Ten Outstanding Young Men of America for 1966 by the United States Jaycees, affiliated with Junior Chamber International, a leadership training and civic organization for people between the ages of 18 and 40. Price's fellow honorees included future United States Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare Joseph A. Califano Jr., and political activist Ralph Nader.
  - Dreyfus Fund [6 folders], 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6-11)
    Robert Price was Executive Vice President and a Director of the Dreyfus Corporation and Investment Officer for the Dreyfus Fund, 1966-1969.
  - Price Capital Corporation. General [5 folders], 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 12-16)
    Robert Price was President then Chairman of the Board of Price Capital Corporation (later called Highland Capital Corporation), 1969-1972.
  - Lazard Frères & Co. [8 folders], 1972-1982 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 17-24)
    Robert Price was Vice President and General Partner of Lazard Frères & Co., Investment Bankers, 1972-1978.
  - Lane Bryant, 1977 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 25)
    Robert Price was elected to the board of directors of Lane Bryant, the women's clothing store chain, in 1977.
  - Intarome Fragrance Corporation, 1978-1986 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 26)
  - Price Communications Corporation [2 folders], 1979-1989 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1-2)
    Robert Price was founder and president of Price Communications Corporation. By 1985 PCC owned and operated 3 television and 11 radio stations, and, in that year, purchased the New York Law Journal.
  - WPCK AM / WIRK FM, 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
  - Telemation, Inc. / TLM Corporation [2 folders], 1986-1990 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4-5)
- Series V. Price personal, 1953-2003
  Series V includes personal material (e.g., correspondence, tax and financial records, résumés, and newspaper compositions) of Robert Price and his wife, Margery, their daughter Eileen (Price) Farbman, and son, Steven Price.
  Series V is divided in three chronologically organized sub-series:
  Sub-series V.A. Robert Price, 1953–2003
  Sub-series V.B. Eileen (Price) Farbman, 1977–1987
  Sub-series V.C. Steven Price, 1975–1988
  - Sub-series V.A. Robert Price, 1953-2003
    - Address / telephone book, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
    - Columbia University School of Law, 1953-1984 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
    - Park Lane Dairy, 1954-1961 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 8)
      Material documenting the sale of Robert Price's father Solomon's grocery business, the Park Lane Dairy (594 Fort Washington Avenue, Manhattan), to the Gristedes supermarket chain.
    - Art, 1959-1965, 1972 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9)
      Documentation of two artworks owned by Price: Everett Shinn's "Roman Amphitheatre" [sic] (1959-1965) and Rembrandt's etching "The Bathers" (1972).
    - Robert Price résumés, circa 1960s-1981 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, 1963-1964, undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 11)
    - Robert & Margery Price. Tax information, 1993 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 12)
    - Robert Price. Charitable contributions, 1996 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 13)
    - Robert Price. Taxes [7 folders], 1998 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 14-20)
    - Price Family Foundation. Taxes [3 folders], 1998-2001 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Checkbook balancer, circa 1972 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
      A small, mechanical adding machine, with stylus, designed to fit in a checkbook. Produced by the Diamond Check Division of Diamond International Corporation beginning in 1972. For more information refer to the example held by the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of American History.
    - Bank statements, canceled checks. Citibank, 1986-1989 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bank statements, canceled checks. Citibank, 2001-2003 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    - Bank statements, canceled checks. Chase, 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1984, undated (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
  - Sub-series V.B. Eileen (Price) Farbman, 1977-1987
    - Eileen Price résumés, college admissions, etc., 1977-circa 1983 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
    - Steven & Eileen Farbman tax papers, 1987 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
  - Sub-series V.C. Steven Price, 1975-1988
    - Bar Mitzvah Haftarah, 1975 March 1 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper profile, 1977 January 7 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 12)
      David C. Berliner, "Children's Express: News Kids on the Block," Washington Post, January 7, 1977.
    - Middle East trip, 1978 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13)
    - Steven Price résumés, circa 1981-1984 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 14)
    - Department of Defense internship, 1982 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 15)
    - Articles written for New York Times, 1980-1983 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 16)
    - Articles written for Brown Daily Herald, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 17)
    - Brochure: "Can you picture Brown without its student newspaper?", circa 1984 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 18)
    - Articles written for Gainesville Sun, 1983 June-August (Offsite-box 7, Folder 19)
    - Brown University, 1981-1984 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 20)
    - Brown University Commencement, 1984 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 21)
    - Columbia University School of Law, 1984, 1988 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 22)
    - Goldman Sachs, 1984 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 23)
    - Taxes, 1988 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 24)